BRYAN MELANSON

30 Cox Marsh Road Torbay, NL A1K1A2

709 749 1273 (cell)

bryanm@mun.ca

SUMMARY

Strong background in project leadership and innovative problem solving partnered with a unique skill set in the creative arts, currently engaged in Memorial University of Newfoundland's Computer Engineering curriculum. Volunteer experience programming autonomous sailboats as part of the MUN SailBot team and mentoring sound crews on first-time filmmaker projects. Accomplished business owner and sound designer with years of experience producing and designing multimedia for clients such as Disney, Fremantle, Collegehumor, ABC and NHL. Several self-produced albums and video art projects featured in national art galleries, as well as lectures on digital production techniques, interactive sound design and digital copyright.

EDUCATION

Memorial University, St. John's NL

Faculty of Engineering and Applied Science
Enrolled in Academic Term IV Computer Engineering, Expected Graduation 2019
Bachelor of Engineering (Co-Op) — 2014-2019

Member of MUN SailBOT team (International Robotic Sailing Regatta 2016)

Free Code Camp, Online

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Expected Graduation 2016

EXPERIENCE

Co-Op Computer Engineering Student, Nalcor Energy

St. John's, NL — December 2015 - April 2016

Developed interactive heat map application for analyzing prices and visualizing correlations within the New York energy market using MATLAB, R and SQL. Initiated migration of heat map functionality to web using R and Google Maps API.

Accomplishments

- Integrated archive features, allowing for the mapping of thousands of hours of reported data analytics not previously available for price forecasting
- Optimized SQL query handling, resulting in significant runtime improvements
- Created functional specifications for features requested by market analysts
- Mapped all power stations and major transmission lines in New York state
- Scripted the mapping of all major external energy markets using R

Owner / Sound Designer, OK+Audio

Montréal, QC — 2011 - 2014

Sound design, recording, editing, composing and mixing duties for podcasts, short films, documentaries, ringtones, audio books, television, video games and commercials. Worked directly with clients to develop and realize contracted audio content from concept, to final optimization.

Accomplishments

- Clients including Disney, ABC, NHL, Ubisoft, NFL, and FremantleMedia
- Game credits include "Starmaker Karaoke", "Island Escape", "Word Dragon", "Stormglass", "All In", "Intruder Alert!" and "Elemental Warriors"
- Commercial credits include web ads for "Assassin's Creed Black Flag", "Are

You Smarter Than a 5th Grader" and "Who Wants to Be a Millionaire"

Production Coordinator, Ludia

Montréal, QC — 2009 - 2011

Lead both in-house and outsourced branches of video and image development for "The Price Is Right -- Facebook", and "The Price Is Right -- Decades" multi-console video games through several complete development cycles.

Accomplishments

- Trained and supervised a team of 15 full-time video editors
- Managed planning, review, implementation and maintenance of over 15,000 in-game assets with accompanying transcriptions
- Worked closely with producers and developers to meet delivery goals
- "TPIR -- Facebook" received 1,000,000 unique users its 1st week

CERTIFICATION

Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore MD

Data Science Specialization (Coursera) — 2015 -- 2016 (In progress)

MCAD Certification Program

Certified SolidWorks Associate (CSWA) — 2015

Defensive Driving

Safety Services Newfoundland Labrador — 2015

Standard First Aid/CPR/AED

St. John Ambulance Canada — December 2015 - December 2016

SKILLS

- Proficient with C++, Javascript, R, Chuck, and Python programming languages, and demonstrated experience with Bash, Git, HTML, SQL, Bootstrap and CSS
- Application skills include Xcode, Sublime Text, Excel, RStudio, MATLAB, Solidworks, Eclipse, MAX MSP, Supercollider, and Adobe Suite
- Experience managing large teams, including hiring, budgeting, quality assurance, team review and optimizing workflow
- Quick to adapt and master new skills; relentless autodidact learner
- Published cartoonist (*The Scope "Everybody Cheer Up" 2007-2009*)
- Fluent in English and French

INTERESTS

- Powerlifting
- US College Football
- Mentoring Youth

REFERENCES

Available upon request